前情提要✦✦✦
我导演新剧的时候
When I direct a new show,
最难的事情就是让演员们相互信任
the hardest part is getting the actors to trust each other.
我在做一档播客
I'm doing a podcast.
一档关于发生在我们大楼里的谋杀案的
A true crime podcast about a murder
真实的犯罪播客
in our own building.
你们和死者有什么关系吗
Are you associated with the deceased?
也许你已经开始调查了
You're probably just starting your investigation,
-正在查找相关信息取证...  -我靠
- looking into all the forensic... ‐ Goddammit.
要是我再碰到一个真实案件的狂热粉...
If I meet one more true crime nut...
翻译　小星星　关止　嘉禾
字　　幕　　侠
关注新浪微博
@FIX字幕侠
翻译　7草　CapitalK
我发现了一些很棒的东西
I am onto something great here.
ZIMUXIA.CN
校对　叮咚
-要多少钱 三万二吗  -现在要三万五了
‐ What was it? 32K? ‐ Now, it's 35.
原 创 翻 译
中英双语字幕
后期　Jason肖　特效　小布
我去哪儿都想往人堆里扎
I tend to make packs wherever I go.
监制　叮咚
我小的时候 还组过少年侦探团
When I was a kid, I had my Hardy Boys pack.
ZIMUXIA.CN
原 创 翻 译
中英双语字幕
梅布尔是个年轻的小姑娘 她保证不会隐瞒我们什么
Mabel is a sweet young woman who promised not to keep secrets from us.
天 她在那儿
Oh my God! There she is!
是那个穿扎染帽衫的人
It's Tie‐Dye Guy!
我没有杀害蒂姆·科诺
I didn't murder Tim Kono.
蒂姆是被杀害的吗 靠 他是对的
Tim was murdered? Damn, he was right.
蒂姆知道他会被杀吗
Tim thought he was gonna get murdered?
他一直想搞一个叫安吉儿的黑市珠宝商人
He'd been trying to take down this black market jewelry dealer named Angel.
蒂姆·科诺是一个在银行工作的独狼
Tim Kono was a loner who worked in a bank.
搞一个黑市珠宝商人
Taking down a black market jewelry dealer
听着有点不自量力 不是吗
seems a little off-brand, don't you think?
也许吧... 不过 我在他房间里发现了这些
Maybe... Then again, I found all these in his apartment.
我们生而孤独
We're all born alone.
除非你是双胞胎啥的
Unless you're a twin or something,
但是双胞胎真的能吓死我
but twins creep me the fuck out.
更别跟我提什么三胞胎
And don't even get me started on triplets
四胞胎... 管他们叫什么呢
or quadrupla... Whatever the fuck they're called.
我不知道 不过那不是重点 我的重点是
I don't know 'cause that's not my point. My point is
我们生而孤独
we're born alone,
孤单地度过大部分时光
spend most of our time alone,
最后孤独地死去
then we all go out alone.
我小时候 有一个电视节目...
When I was a kid, there was this show on TV...
"赫尔曼的头脑" 记得吗
Herman's Head. You remember this shit?
主角赫尔曼脑子里
Herman was this dude who had
有一群想象的小人 给他建议
these imaginary people in his head, advising him.
世上根本没有一见钟情这种事
There's no such thing as love at first sight!
一个总是很紧张 一个很浪漫...
One was the nervous one, one was the romantic one...
我... 我记不清所有的细节了 但是我对那部剧他妈的印象深刻
I-I can't remember all the details, but I remember the fuck outta that show.
我很喜欢这部剧 因为老年赫尔曼不孤独
And I liked it 'cause old Herman wasn't alone.
你懂我的意思吗 他脑子里总有一群人陪着他
You know what I mean? He had these people in his head.
很长一段时间里 我都在学赫尔曼
For a long time, I played it like Herman.
就只有我和我脑子里的一群给我建议的人
Just me and the people advising me in my head.
然后我玩太过 把事情搞砸了
And then I went and fucked that up by listening
因为我太听那个浪漫混蛋的话了
to that romantic fucker in my head a little too much.
各位听众 大家好
Hey, podcast listeners.
这里是"大楼里只有谋杀" 我们感到饥饿时...
Here at Only Murders in the Building, when we get hungry...
嘿
Hey.
你干嘛呢 我们不是说好要一起装修婴儿房吗
What you doing? We said we're doing the nursery together.
我等了 等了很久了
I waited. As long as I could.
也许猫咪伊芙琳的脚印说明不了什么
Perhaps Evelyn the cat's paw prints meant nothing.
但也许它们是整件事的关键...
But perhaps they were key to the entire...
不要让我们未出生的孩子
Do not subject our unborn child
忍受这种真实案件的胡话了 求你了
to this true crime bullshit, please!
这个很可爱
This one is cute.
没有招呼吻吗
I don't get a kiss hello?
我的错 我的错 当然有啦
Oh, my bad. My bad. I got you.
... 其实看不出来红色...
... can't actually see the color red...
你觉得我闻不出你身上的烟味吗
You think I won't smell that cigarette on you?
别提了
Don't start.
我今天接到个小孩死亡的案子
I had a dead kid today.
这边实时为您播报...
I'm coming to you live from...
是个小女孩
A little girl.
继父
Stepfather.
虐待 就那些
Abuse. All of that.
好吧
Alright.
可是卡里姆出生后你必须戒
But this shit stops when Kareem comes.
谁他妈是卡里姆
Who the fuck is Kareem?
-不是我儿子吧  -卡里姆·阿布杜尔-贾巴尔[前NBA球员]
- Not my son. ‐ Kareem Abdul-Jabbar?
-所以呢  -运动员 学者
‐ So? ‐ Is an athlete, a scholar,
公平正义积极分子
an activist?
卡里姆·哈迪森在"不同的世界"里演德维恩·韦恩呢 我不在乎
And Kareem Hardison is Dwayne Wayne on A Different World. I don't care.
-是卡迪姆  -什么
‐ Kadeem. ‐ What?
那是卡迪姆·哈迪森
Kadeem Hardison.
我就是这么说的 是一样的
That's what I said. It's the same shit.
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
我还想着你今天能早点回来帮我一起弄这个呢
You know, I was hoping you'd be home in time to help me with this.
你刚刚没听到我跟你说什么了吗
Did you not just hear me tell you about my day today?
就只是....
Just...
不要最后变成杰格森 迪 好吗
don't end up like Jerguson, Dee. Okay?
-我不想要那样的结婚对象  -好 行
- That's not who I married. ‐ Alright. Okay.
霍华德·莫里斯住在阿尔科尼亚的3D号公寓
Howard Morris lives at the Arconia in apartment 3D,
里面一股猫味儿
a place pungent with cat dander.
阿尔科尼亚
The Arconia?
但比那个味儿更浓烈的是
But even stronger than the odor
霍华德对蒂姆·科诺的怒火
was Howard's rage toward Tim Kono.
什么玩意儿 不 那个我已经结案了
What the fuck? No, I-I closed that case.
我靠 他们说的是你
Oh shit, that's you they're talking about?
-什么 他们他妈的说什么了  -这样吧
- What? W-what the fuck are they saying? ‐ You know what?
-我把它关了吧  -不 那就是自杀
- Let's just turn it off. ‐ No, that was a suicide,
一目了然
open and shut.
好吧 可是 不好意思... 那猫爪印呢
Okay, but, um, sorry... What about the paw prints?
因为那只猫
Because the cat
是后来才进去的 他们... 他们发现了
that came in after, and they... they found it.
你他妈认真的吗
You fuckin' for real?
所以呢
So, what?
凶手是只猫
The cat did it?
不 认真的 我们... 所以是猫干的
No, for real. Let-let's just... So, the cat did it?
你为什么要听这种垃圾节目
Why are you listening to this shit?
我看的"院内狗狗 园艺密友"都在推特上安利这个播客
My Yard Dog Homies were boosting it on Twitter.
这些人 他们...
I mean, these guys, they're...
他们傻乎乎的 但他们很会讲故事
they're dopey, but they tell the story really well.
对 我不... 我不讲故事
Yeah, I don't... I don't tell stories.
而且我接手的案子从不犯错
And I don't make mistakes on my cases.
-等等 你要去哪  -你觉得呢
‐ Wait, where are you going? ‐ Where do you think?
-迪 别这样  -你知道...
‐ Dee, come on. ‐ You know...
你没必要拿工作的事堵我的 至少今天没必要
you didn't have to hit me with the work shit. Not today.
我们继续盯着这些珠宝
We continued staring at the jewels
就像一个打了很久的节拍
for what felt like a beat too long.
我在蒂姆的公寓找到的
I found them in Tim's apartment.
我们离开之后 我自己又回去了
I went back alone after we left.
你自己一个人回去了吗
You went back without us?
我知道你为什么不带查尔斯 但是为什么不带我
Charles I get, but without me?
我帮他找的这个
I found him this one.
还有这个 都是从安吉儿那搞来的
And this one. These are all from Angel.
安吉儿是谁
Who is Angel?
我只知道这个名字
That's the only name I got.
科诺痴迷于从安吉儿那买珠宝
Kono was obsessed with buying pieces from Angel.
但还没买到真正想要的 蒂姆就死了
Sucks Tim died before he got the one he really wanted.
他想要的是哪个
And which one was that?
我好像有照片
Uh, I got a pic somewhere.
他已经找了很多年了 我翻翻照片
He'd been trying to track it down for years. I can dig it up.
好的 麻烦了
Yes, please,
找到了立刻发信息给我
and text it to me as soon as you find it.
-还有我  -还有我
‐ Me, too. ‐ Me, three!
发给我就行
Just me.
我帮蒂姆牵线了一个珠宝商
You know, I hooked Tim up with my jewelry connection,
卡特 来谈谈他想要的那件东西
Cutter, to talk about that piece he wanted.
天哪
Oh my God!
这反转真是令人难以置信
The twists and turns of this are just unbelievable.
就像喝醉的矮精灵变出来的彩虹
It's like a‐a rainbow crafted by a drunken leprechaun.
[爱尔兰传说中像小矮人的精灵]
我这么说是因为我有四分之三的爱尔兰血统
I can say that 'cause I'm three‐quarters Irish,
然后我有一点小小的酗酒问题
and I have a teeny bit of a drinking problem.
等下 蒂姆本来和卡特约好今天在这见面的
Wait. Tim was supposed to meet Cutter here today.
我猜你不是卡特吧
I'm gonna guess you're not Cutter.
你都到贝波特了
You come to Bayport,
这还要那位戴帽子的女士告诉我吗
I have to hear it from Miss Skullcap over here?
你都不打给我打个电话吗
You don't call me?
嘿 妈妈
Hey, Mom.
大楼里只有谋杀
第一季 第 6 集
第六集
保护与服务
那个被心理虐待成瘾的母亲养大的
And that sad and lonely boy
孤独可怜男孩不是别人...
raised by a psychologically abusive mother was none other...
正是斯蒂芬·约书亚·桑德海姆
than Stephen Joshua Sondheim.
我再告诉你一些关于斯蒂夫的事
And let me tell you something about Steve.
当他在场上时 是一件好事
When he is on his game, it's a blessing.
-他不在时 我也很有耐心  -嗯
-And when's he's not, I'm patient. ‐ Mm.
看
Hey.
塔夫给我发了蒂姆的那张照片
Tavo texted me that photo from Tim.
蒂姆
Tim?
住在阿尔科尼亚的蒂姆吗
From the Arconia, Tim?
他对奥斯卡做出那种事你居然还跟他有联系吗
Why are you still in contact with that boy after what he did to Oscar?
我没有 妈妈 他已经死了
I'm not, Mommy. He died.
-他被杀了  -被杀了吗
‐ He was murdered. ‐ Murdered?
-就在大楼里  -听起来是不是很吸引人
‐ In the building. ‐ Catchy, right?
天哪
Ay, dios mio.
那地方不适合你
That place is no good for you.
我就知道我不该让你回去
I knew I shouldn't have let you go back there.
让我吗 我已经成年了 妈妈
Let me? I'm grown, Mommy.
我们在调查这件事 你女儿帮了很大的忙
We're investigating, and your daughter has been a big help in this.
-调查是什么意思  -意思是我们
‐ What do you mean investigating? I mean, we,
和你女儿一起做了一个播客来讲蒂姆·科诺的谋杀案
and your daughter, are producing a podcast about Tim Kono's murder.
我让你回去是因为你向我保证
I only let you go back there because you promised me
会专心搞你的设计事业
you were focusing on your design career.
别再说是你让我去的了
Stop saying that you let me.
这个播客也不算什么
And a podcast is nothing.
你这样跟我们那十七个听众说
Well, tell that to our 17 subscribers.
哇 十七个 算好吗
Wow. Seventeen, is that good?
-不算  -我女儿控制不了自己
‐ No. ‐ My daughter can't help herself.
她把自己困在了过去
She's trapped in the past.
但是 你们...
But, you...
你们俩几岁了 八十吗
How old are you two? 80?
告诉你
I'll have you know that I am in
我才六十多 不到六十五
my very early mid‐60s.
把我女儿拖回过去 让她回到那段对她来说最糟糕的时光吗
Dragging my little girl back into the worst thing that ever happened to her?
我已经不是小姑娘了
Look, I'm not a little girl!
我朋友 我们的朋友 佐伊
My friend, our friend, Zoe died
在新年晚会的时候 死在了阿尔科尼亚的房顶上
at a New Year's Eve party on the roof of the Arconia.
我们觉得蒂姆看到了事情发生的经过
And we think Tim saw what really happened.
-但他没有告诉任何人  -奥斯卡背锅进了监狱
‐ But he never told anybody. ‐ Oscar got blamed and went away,
但他现在出来了 我也没事了
but he's out now, and I'm fine.
被困在过去
Is fine not being able to finish anything or focus
无法完成任何事或者集中注意 这也算没事吗
because your mind is trapped in the past?
-别说了  -害怕夜晚也算没事吗
‐ Please stop! ‐ Temores nocturnos fine?
"未提交"是什么意思
Wait, what? "Not submitted"?
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
毒性分析申请表
已提交
未提交
我以为已经送去技术部了
Oh, I thought I sent you to IT.
他们怎么样 威廉姆斯
How they hangin', Williams?
一天不如一天 杰格森
Lower by the day, Jerguson.
不愧是你
That's my guy.
都是我的错
It's my fault.
我那时忙于工作
I was always working.
我姐姐很有钱 所以当她说
So, when my rich sister offered to take Mabel
可以接梅布尔去度假 我想着...
for the school breaks, I thought...
多好啊
qué maravilloso.
她可以去大城市
She'd go to the city,
去看看那些博物馆和戏剧...
see museums and plays...
能激励她怀揣远大理想
be inspired to dream big.
如果是你看着自己唯一的孩子
You try watching your only child,
曾经那么聪明 那么自信...
so smart, so sure of herself...
然后沉溺于悲伤
turn into a ghost from grief.
你们还会想要做那样的播客吗
Then see if you want to make a podcast about it.
我们不知道这些事
We didn't know about that.
看起来我们不知道的事... 还很多
We didn't know about a lot... it seems.
但你女儿很优秀
But, your daughter is extraordinary.
她很有趣
She's funny,
-直觉很准...  -很奇怪
-intuitive... ‐ Weird.
是最好层面的奇怪
But, in‐in‐in the best ways.
你喜欢的人都很奇怪
The way all your favorite people are weird.
你们有没有这种经历 你搞砸了某件事
Have you ever felt like there was something you screwed up
非常糟
so bad,
然后你永远不会原谅自己
you'll never forgive yourself?
嗯...
Well...
对我来说
For me,
就是让她在那栋该死的公寓里浪费时间
it was letting her spend time at that damn apartment.
麻烦你们离开她吧
Please leave her be.
让她向前走 而不是向后
Let her move forward, not back.
妈妈
Mommy.
-谢谢款待  -对 谢谢
‐ Thank you for dinner. ‐ Yeah, th‐thank you.
她应该是对的
You know, she's probably right.
反正这整件事都很愚蠢
This whole thing was stupid anyways.
这事意味着很多
It was many things,
我觉得不一定是愚蠢的
but I'm not sure it was stupid.
为什么
Why?
我是个陌生人 对你们说了很多谎话
I'm a stranger that lied to you a bunch,
你们是两个拉我开播客的路人
and you're two randos that dragged me into a podcast.
"路人"是指那种无关紧要的人
"Rando" is a slang for a person of no significance.
-我可以根据上下文理解 不过还是谢谢你  -不客气
‐ I used context clues, but thank you. ‐ You're welcome.
你们还是可以继续做播客
You could still do the podcast though.
也可以学着用推特 并不难
Can learn how to use Twitter. It's not that hard.
别玩抖音
Don't do TikTok.
梅布尔 这段时间...
Mabel, it's been, uh...
是我这十年来觉得活得最带劲的
it's been the most alive I've felt in a decade.
我也是
Me, too.
那么…
So, uh...
再见
Goodbye.
我们被吼了
We got yelled at.
-被一个妈妈  -我知道
- By a mom. ‐ I know.
我很震惊
I'm shook.
这是梅布尔教我的
Mabel taught me that word.
-彼此彼此  -这是自然规律
- Same. ‐ You know, it's a law of nature.
长岛上从来就没发生过什么好事
Nothing good ever happens on Long Island.
健肠奶真好喝
Gut Milk is really good.
是吧 我有腹肌全靠它了
Right?! I think it's giving me abs.
13%的酒精
13% alcohol.
干杯
Cheers.
我们有过一段美好的时光
We had a good run,
但我们可能没办法继续下去了
but we can't possibly go on.
完全同意
Fully agree.
这到底是为什么呢
And why is that exactly?
这是梅布尔的生活
This is Mabel's life.
我们不能利用她的痛苦 扮演侦探
We can't exploit her pain, playing detective.
每一个真实的犯罪故事
Every true crime story
对某些人来说是真实生活
is actually true for someone.
你刚刚才发现吗
And this is just occurring to you?
我觉得 谋杀案涉及到个人了
I guess it feels personal now.
因为维尼 我早就觉得这涉及到个人了
It already felt personal to me 'cause of Winnie.
谁是维尼
Who's Winnie?
谁… 你在开玩笑吗
Who... Are you kidding me?!
我的狗 维尼
My dog! Winnie!
还在中毒恢复期...
Who's recovering from being poisoned...
你把她忘得一干二净 我很伤心
The fact that you forgot about her completely is deeply concerning to me.
为什么 我们几乎不了解对方
Why? We barely know each other.
梅布尔说得对 我们都是陌生人
Mabel was right. We're all randos.
我们当然了解彼此
Of course we know each other!
我父母还健在吗
Are my parents dead or alive?
-已经去世了  -猜得对
‐ Dead. ‐ Lucky guess.
是梅布尔吗
Is that Mabel?
不 是泰迪 我们的赞助商
No, it's Teddy. Our sponsor.
"过来找我
"Come to me.
我们聊聊"
We need to speak."
全部大写 不祥之兆
All caps. Ominous.
不 他就喜欢这么打字
No, that's just the way he types.
但看上去还是挺糟的
But it still seems bad.
你愿意和我一起去吗
Would you mind coming with me?
还是说我对你来说只是陌生人
Or am I too rando?
你知道我20多岁时几乎没有约过会吗
You know I barely dated my entire 20s?
你知道吗
Did you know that?
我一个人
I was alone.
然后
Then,
在某个周二晚上
on a random Tuesday night,
我让这个女人靠边停车
I pull over this woman
因为我抓到她边开车边发短信
who I caught texting while driving.
然后这个女人竟敢
And then this broad had the audacity
当着我的面撒谎
to lie to my face
说她没有打字
and say that she wasn't texting.
我没有撒谎
I wasn't lying!
你还当着我的面撒谎
You still lying to me in my face!
但是 我知道…
But, I knew...
以后…
then...
我再也不会是一个人了
I wasn't gonna be alone anymore.
现在 我们马上有个孩子了...
And now, we got this kid coming...
卡里姆
Kareem.
不 除非我死了 不要叫这个名字
No. Over my dead body. We're not doing it.
我只需要知道我能做好这件事
I just need to know that I'm gonna be good at this.
-你会的  -不你不知道
‐ You will be. ‐ No, you don't know that.
我知道
I do!
就像我知道那些录播客的人有所发现
Just like I knew those podcast guys were onto something.
你遗漏了一些东西 对吗
You missed something, didn't you?
毒性分析申请…
The tox reports...
没有提交
they weren't submitted.
还有受害者的电话...
And the victim's phone...
没有给技术部
never made it to IT.
天呐 对的
Oh my God, yes!
所以现在 你冲过去
So now, you swoop in there
像个英雄老大一样重开案子
and reopen the case like a goddamn hero boss,
-然后就…  -宝贝 不行
- and just...  ‐ Baby, no.
当他们不提交某些东西的时候
When they don't submit something,
就意味着他们不想插手
that means they want all hands off,
我不能因为重开一个已经结案的案子就去找警长
and I can't get up to sergeant by opening a case that I already closed.
不 这样不行
No. That's not how it works.
我们不能这么做
That's what we're not gonna do.
但是我们要做的是...
But what we will do...
我们进去
is that we gonna go in here
把婴儿房收拾好
and work on this nursery
-为我的基思做准备  -基思
- for my man Keith. ‐ Keith?
是的 这听上去很不... 卡里姆
Oh yes. You know, it's not quite... Kareem.
-是的 这不…  -但也没那么烂
‐ Yeah, it's not... ‐ But it's also not lame as fuck.
-我能理解  -好的
‐ I could dig it. ‐ Okay.
-基思...  -谢谢
‐ Keith... ‐ Thank you.
我觉得我会记得这个
Wow, I think I would've remembered this.
我抑郁的时候
Yeah. Well, during my depressing years,
我妈妈让我读"生命之树"
my mom told me to read about the Tree of Life.
不过 我亲手做了个
Instead, I just made one.
很赞
It's amazing.
这个"法律与秩序: 特殊受害者"的海报很难让人忘记
Could never forget the SVU poster.
你对斯特布勒的迷恋真奇怪
Weird‐ass crush you had on Stabler.
史上最性感的罪犯就在这里
The hottest criminal mind ever is right here.
他身材保持得很好
And he kept it pretty tight.
我知道和你所经历的相比这算不了什么 但是...
I know it's nothing compared to what you went through, but...
那件事发生后 我过得也不容易
I had it pretty hard after everything happened.
我知道
Yeah.
看来咱俩都一样
Seems like we all did.
-这是什么  -别 不要
- What's this? Huh? ‐ Oh. No, no.
-梅布尔六年级  -太羞耻了
‐ Mabel Sixth Grade? ‐ So embarrassing.
-我想看 等一下  -不 不想给你看
‐ Yes, please. Hold on. ‐ No! Don't want you to see it!
-一起看啊 过来  -我不想看…
‐ Have a seat! Come on! ‐ I don't wanna look at...
我们一起看 过来
We'll look at it together. Here.
哇 这个可爱小男孩是谁
Whoa! Who is this cute little boy? Huh?
我很可爱 我不知道你在…
Um, I was adorable. I don't know what you're...
你对西尔维娅做了什么 让她把你剪成西瓜头
What did you do to Silvia for her to give you a bowl cut?
现在 你已经失去了看这些的权利 干得好
And now, you've lost the right to look at these. So, good job.
我的少年侦探团
该死
Damn.
天呐
Holy shit.
塔夫发的图
Tavo's text.
这什么鬼
What the hell?
为什么蒂姆要找佐伊死的那晚
Why was Tim after the ring that Zoe had on
-戴着的戒指  -不
- the night she died? ‐ No.
不 她那天没戴
She didn't have it on.
至少她死的时候没有
Not when she died.
你不会忘掉自己女朋友的尸体躺在地上的样子
You don't forget the image of your girlfriend's body on the ground.
但是照片上有啊
But it's right here.
所以 可能是她在死之前丢了这只戒指
So, does this mean she lost the ring before she went over?
能不说这个了吗
Yo, can we stop now?
-你还好吗  -我们能不能
‐ Are you okay? ‐ Can we please spend, like,
不谈她的死 两分钟就行
two minutes talking about not death?
我今天只想... 和你在一起
All I wanted to do today was just... be with you.
这一刻我设想过很多次
I've thought about this moment a lot.
我一直很想你
I've thought about you a lot.
我也是
Me, too.
我想...
I think...
我好像一直在等你
I've kind of been waiting for you.
抱歉 我不是这个意思
Uh, sorry. I‐I don't mean waiting for you
不是一直只是等着...
like I was waiting...
不是只在等你 我不是什么都没做...
waiting for you. I didn't save myself for...
不是不是 我懂 当然
No, no, yeah, yeah. Yeah. For sure.
我做了很多其他事 我...
I did other things. I...
我工作 我去参加派对
I worked. I went to parties.
我留过很难看的刘海 躲了一个月没见人
I got bangs that were awful, and I had to hide for a month.
不 我打赌你肯定还是很好看
No, I‐I bet you looked hot.
你堵输了
You'd lose that bet.
好吧 让我亲自看看 刘海是不是到这里...
Well, let's see for myself. Were they like the lower...
再长一点而且它们有点卷...
Little longer and then they did, like, a curl...
天哪 你说的对
Oh God. You're right.
刘海... 太丑了 我不能当作没看过
They're... It's horrible. I can't unsee that.
你有没有感觉自己有时候
Do‐do you ever feel like you've been
[访谈节目为"吉米今夜秀" 主持人为吉米·法伦]
过于鼓舞人心 辛达 你知道
too inspirational, Cinda? You know,
现在好像每个人都有播客
like everyone has a podcast now.
确实 现在播客火得有点过头
It has gotten a little out there.
就好像 我记得那个演布拉佐斯的演员吧
Like, I guess the actor who played Brazzos
-现在就有自己的播客  -什么
- has his own podcast now?  - What?
等下 查尔斯...
Wait, Charles, uh...
哈登·丘奇 不对 我弄混了
Haden Church? No, I'm mixing him up.
他演过布拉佐斯 而且他
He's Brazzos, and he's
正在他住的上西区大楼里调查一桩真实的谋杀案
investigating a real murder, uh, in his Upper West Side building
和一个戏剧导演一起
with a theater director
还有他们中某一个人的孙女
and one of their granddaughters. Wow.
而且他们的头号嫌疑人是斯汀
And their prime suspect is Sting.
不是吧
No!
-不是吧  -真的 他们播客的标题是
- No!  - Yes! The title of their podcast
迪马斯鸡肉卷出品...
is Dimas Chicken Wraps Presents...
冒号 大楼里只有谋杀
Colon. Only Murders In The Building.
我的确... 的确很喜欢迪马斯鸡肉卷
Well, I do... I do love a Dimas Chicken Wrap.
超喜欢 大家都喜欢迪马斯鸡肉卷
Love 'em! Everybody loves a Dimas Chicken Wrap.
我天
My goodness.
泰迪...
Teddy...
你们知道...
Do you understand...
法伦在希腊有多有名吗
how huge Fallon is in Greece?
你们知道我在尼西罗斯岛的表兄弟们
Do you know what my cousins back on Nisyros
看到这个节目会怎么样吗
are gonna do when they see this?
他们会发疯的 奥利
They're gonna shit themselves, Ollie!
他们会蹲在他们羊圈里
They're gonna squat right down in their goat fields
嫉妒得屁滚尿流
and shit themselves in envy!
那真是...
That's...
-真...  -有画面感啊
- Wow. Yeah, that's...  - quite an image.
你成功了 你们直接全垒打了
You did it! You fucking homered!
你们的"播客"才出了两集
Two episodes of your "podcast,"
法伦就提到了我的名字
and my name is in Fallon's mouth!
你们之后还有很多集吧 请告诉我
You've got more coming, right? Please tell me
-你们很快会上线更多集吧  -当然
- you've got more coming soon! - Of course.
-是的 当然  -实际上 我们遇到了点小麻烦...
-Yes. Yes, of course. ‐ Actually, we've had a setback...
加上大量精彩的曲折情节
With lots of juicy twists and turns
还有每小时至少出现四次迪马斯的广告
and room for at least four Dimas spots in every hour?
至少四次 当然
At least. Sure.
跟你们说 我觉得自己就像个自豪的老爸
I gotta tell you, I feel like a proud papa.
我的宝贝们
My boys.
现在...
Now...
我要给你们写张支票...
I'm writing you a check...
这会是一大笔钱
and it's gonna be large.
而且 我不接受反对
But, I don't want a fight.
五万用来赞助接下来的三集
50,000 for the next three episodes.
我们不能收下 泰迪
We can't accept that, Teddy.
-别这么说  -拜托 别这么说
‐ Don't say that. ‐ Oh please, don't say that.
我们的一个搭档退出了 所以这样不太好
Well, uh, we lost one of our partners, and it wouldn't be right.
过来 来 快点
Come here. Come here, right now.
看到这个了吗
You see that?
这枚硬币是我家族的传家宝
That coin is my entire family legacy.
你们知道希腊和亚美尼亚的大屠杀吗
You know of the Greek and Armenian Holocaust?
这是我的奶奶
My grandmother.
我奶奶伊万吉丽娅
My yiayia Evangelia
在土耳其士兵开始屠杀整个希腊的时候
was a young woman when the Turks
还很年轻
started slaughtering all the Greeks,
他们被迫逃离家园
forcing them to flee their home.
那时是没有银行的 所以女人们都把
They didn't have banks back then, so women would wear necklaces
家里的毕生积蓄换成金币
with their family's life savings
做成项链挂在脖子上
in gold coins around their necks.
亡命逃跑中 我的奶奶和一位土耳其士兵
Desperate to flee, my yiayia made a trade
做了笔交易
with a Turkish soldier.
用项链换了一个去美国的船位
Her necklace for a spot on a boat to take her to America.
那个士兵给她留了两枚硬币
The soldier let her keep two coins.
一枚用来以后开始新生活
One to invest in a new future,
另一枚当作幸运币
and one for luck.
奶奶...
Yiayia...
紧紧握住这几枚硬币...
held tight to those coins...
漂过了
through a sea
被家人们的鲜血和砍下的四肢
made red with blood and the chopped‐off limbs
染成红色的海洋
of her whole family.
最终到达了埃利斯岛
Till she finally made it to Ellis Island.
还紧紧地握着这两枚硬币
Still clutching those two coins.
她用其中一枚
She used one
开了家小小的三明治店
to start a small sandwich shop,
另一枚她一直留着...
and the other she held onto...
传给了我爸爸
and passed it on to my father,
让他永远铭记并传承
so he'd never forget the sacrifices
为了我们迪马斯家族的荣光
made to carry on
所做出的牺牲
our proud Dimas name.
然后你爸爸传给了你
And your father passed it to you.
其实 我俩想法不太一样
We, uh, didn't see eye‐to‐eye.
实际上 他还发誓就算把这枚硬币带进坟墓
In fact, he vowed he'd take the coin to his grave
也不给我
rather than give it to me.
很明显他改变了想法
Well, obviously he changed his mind.
或是我把那个混蛋从地下挖出来后 从他冰冷的手中夺过来的
Or I dug the fucker up and ripped it out of his cold dead hands.
什么... 鬼
What... the fuck?
真厉害
Th‐that's so good.
你... 你骗到我了
Tha... You fooled me.
我奶奶伊万吉丽娅教我
My yiayia Evangelia taught me
要给那些忠诚于你的人
to make investments in the people
注资支持
who've been loyal to you,
哪怕有风险
even when there's risk.
我注资的时候
I have a whole separate business
以她的名义开了独立的公司账户
in her name where I do this work.
所以 拜托了...
So, please...
看在我的面子上 收下吧
do me this honor.
奥斯卡吻技怎么样
So, is Oscar a good kisser?
妈妈
Mommy!
我注意到他看你时的表情了
I saw the way he was looking at you.
就像是你们还是青少年时那样看你
The same way he looked at you when you were teenagers.
我真希望能回到那个时候
I wish I could go back in time to those days.
然后呢
And do what?
我不知道
I don't know.
-让你一直待在那时直到...  -直到...
Keep you there until... ‐ Till...
直到我死了
Until I'm dead.
然后 你就能做任何你想做的事了
Then, you can go do whatever you wanted.
老人总是让人感伤的角色
The old men are sad characters.
大概 是这样的吧
I guess. Sort of.
在很长一段时间里 他们是最先成为我的朋友的人
They're also the first friends I've had in a really long time.
-说真的 他们多大年纪  -他们真的 很老了
‐ But seriously, how old are they? Yeah. ‐ They're, like, really old.
我得把这事搞定
I have to see this through.
我得知道真相
I have to figure this out.
你小时候我没怎么能给你讲故事
I could never read you stories when you were little.
我试过 但是...
I tried, but...
你总是想跳过剧情 直接知道结局是什么
you always wanted to skip right to the end.
你总是想知道发生了什么
You always needed to know what happened.
宝贝...
Baby...
要是我们有扇通向蒂姆·科诺的想法的窗 就好了
If only we had a window into Tim Kono's mind.
大楼里只有谋杀
保护与服务
这样就能知道他在生前最后几天里
Some way to know more of what he was doing in the days
大楼里只有谋杀
保护与服务
做了什么 招致了他的死亡 笔记本电脑
leading up to his death. A laptop,
日历 或是任何事实证据都能让我们更接近
a calendar, any piece of physical evidence that would bring us closer
真相
to the truth.
我不记得"赫尔曼之颅"的剧情是怎么结束的
I don't remember how Herman's Head ended,
但是我推断最后是他找到了那个女孩
but I suspect it ended with him finally finding the girl.
或者那个男人 我一直分不清他是男是女
Or the guy. I could never tell with Herman.
也不再需要那些人试图了解他的想法
And not needing those advisors in his head anymore.
给 梅布尔·莫拉
C10 阿尔科尼亚公寓
要是我的话 我就会这么做
That's how I would've done it.
赫尔曼不需要他们因为赫尔曼不孤独
Herman doesn't need them 'cause he's not alone anymore.
但是 哪怕你不孤独
But even if you're not alone,
也不代表你不需要帮助
it doesn't mean you don't need help sometimes.
我们节目有1265下载...
We have 1,265 downlo...
1267了
1,267!
我们为什么不得不受欢迎啊
Why do we have to get popular now?
显然 人们还在看实时电视节目
Apparently, people still watch live TV.
我在NBC导演"福音"直播的时候这群观众都去哪儿了呢
Where was this audience when I directed Godspell Live on NBC?
-是你导演的吗  -不 本来应该是
‐ That was you? ‐ No, but it should've been.
确实 我理解不了他们
See, I‐I'm not getting them.
我按了刷新 但是不起作用
I'm hitting refresh, and nothing is working.
你又进飞行模式了
You're in airplane mode. Again.
-怎么了  -你知道我的手机设定
- What? ‐ You knew my phone settings.
说明我对你还挺重要的
I'm not a rando.
行了 我们得解决这破事了
Alright, we need to deal with this mess.
你的金主给了我们五万块
Your dip man gave us $50,000.
对 而且...
Right, and‐and...
我们不能收这笔钱因为...
we can't accept it because...
我们同意不能
we agreed not to profit off
从我们小朋友的悲伤中获利
our young friend's tragedy.
是的 所以我们只能拿着这张支票
That's right, so we have to take that check,
然后把它撕了
and we have to rip it up.
-现在就要吗  -是的
- Now? ‐ Yes.
我觉得我们现在就应该把它撕了
I think we have to rip it up, uh, now.
-等等  -怎... 谢天谢地  怎么了
- Wait, wait, wait! ‐ Wha... Thank God. What?
这是什么账号 这可不是泰迪的名字
What's this account? It's not in Teddy's name.
他说他有个独立的商业账户给...
Well, he said he had a separate business account for...
看看这个名字
Look at the name.
"安吉儿有限责任公司"
"Angel, Inc."
不不不 泰迪不是那个蒂姆·科诺试着扳倒的安吉儿
Oh no, no, no. Teddy is not the Angel that Tim Kono was trying to bring down.
我还在想
I was wondering
他说他奶奶的名字的时候
when he said his yiayia's name.
伊万吉丽娅
Evangelia.
安吉儿
Angel.
-你不敲门的吗  -嘿
- You don't knock? ‐ Hey.
敲门的女人可不会名留历史
Women who knock rarely make history.
这是和解的礼物 斯尔维亚家的玉米粽
A peace offering. Silvia's tamales,
我搞来了些鹰嘴豆泥
and I picked up some hummus.
这鹰嘴豆泥昨天就过期了
This hummus expired yesterday.
但是你不管怎么样都会吃的
But we both know you're gonna eat it.
确实 没说错
I know. It's true.
听着...
Look...
我很抱歉 我骗了你们
I'm really sorry about lying to you guys.
在各种场合 持续了好几周
On multiple fronts. For weeks.
说了许多谎话
An inordinate amount of lying.
都快成反社会了
It was borderline sociopathic.
只是...
It's just...
对我来说信任别人是一件很难的事情
very hard for me to trust people.
说实话 对我来说要喜欢别人都很难
Honestly, it's pretty hard for me to even like people.
但是你们...
But you guys...
你们真的要我把话说出口吗
Are you really gonna make me say it?
我还是想听到那些词的 是的
I'd kinda like to hear the words, yes.
顺便记得给我们排个名 我很想知道你更喜欢谁
Also rank us. I'm dying to know who your favorite is.
我真的想做这个播客
I want to do this podcast.
我真的希望能和你们一起做完它
I have to finish this with you guys.
那也太...
That...
太敷衍了
is so rando.
这个手势...
That...
太不合适了
is not the right gesture.
-给我点玉米粽吧  -等等
‐ Give me those tamales. ‐ Wait.
我还有一个和解礼物
My final peace offering.
有人在前台留了这个给我
Someone left this for me at the front desk.
这是蒂姆·科诺的手机
It's Tim Kono's phone.
-什么  -哇
- What? - Whoa!
但是我们得找到密码
But we need to find the password.
-好吧...  -这样啊...
‐ Oy... ‐ Oh...
我们也有新发现
Well, we got one for you.
这个
Here.
和安吉儿...
Say hello...
问好吧
to Angel.
泰迪·迪马斯吗
Teddy Dimas?
等等 你是想说...
Wait, so you're saying...
没错 我们的主要赞助商
That's right. Our prime sponsor
现在是我们的主要嫌疑犯了
is now our prime suspect.
真棒
Ooh, that's good.
ZIMUXIA.CN
关注新浪微博
@FIX字幕侠
这很适合当一集的结尾
That'll make a great last line for an episode.